Guide to the Human Rights Watch records,
Rare Book and Manuscript Library Columbia University Libraries
Asia Watch records,
1978-1997
[Bulk, 1987-1997].
Human Rights Watch (Organization)
152.5 linear ft. (122 record cartons)
Columbia University. Rare Book and Manuscript Library New York, NY. 10027
HR#0002
7748599
Record Group 6 documents Asia Watch's (AW) three-branched program of documentation, campaigning, and lobbying in order to promote the observance of internationally recognized human rights norms throughout the region. Utilizing this paradigm, for example, AW tackled such difficult issues as economic aid and democratization efforts; the plight of political prisoners and refugees; the advancement of the freedom of expression, the suppression of political violence in Indonesia and Sri Lanka; and the effect of AIDS and prostitution on women. In the late 1990s, AW expanded its mission by seeking allies within the NGO and business communities in Europe and Japan in order to bring more direct pressure on human rights offenders.
Historical Note
This Record Group contains the records of Human Rights Watch/Asia (AW). Established in 1985, Asia Watch monitors and promotes the observance of internationally recognized human rights in Asia. Since its founding, AW has kept refining a three-pronged strategy of documentation, campaigning, and lobbying to expose abuses in the region. By the late 1980s, this strategy came to fruition with regard to China. To illustrate, even before the Tiananmen Square Massacre, AW had been working with Chinese human rights groups to support efforts to record the plight of Chinese political prisoners. In early May 1989, in turn, an AW mission traveled to Beijing in order to speak with pro-democracy demonstrators. These labors were combined with first-hand reports and lobbying campaigns before Congress. Asia Watch China Specialist, Robin Munro, for example, wrote an eyewitness account of the Tiananmen Square Massacre. AW executive staff, in turn, became vocal advocates for sanctions against China on Capitol Hill. Finally, AW set up a branch headquarters in Hong Kong. This office enabled AW to tap into the extensive information-gathering network in Hong Kong. It also facilitated work on behalf of pro-democracy activists who escaped there after the massacre.
Through the 1990s, through their three-pronged model, AW had expanded the number of countries it covered, the issues it addressed and the advocacy techniques it employed in the region. AW, for example, began seeking allies within the NGO and business communities in Europe and Japan in order to bring more direct pressure on human rights offenders in Asia.
Scope and Content
Materials include correspondence and e-mail communications, mission reports, testimonies and interviews, addresses and contact lists, confidential interoffice memos, legal and advocacy material, internal planning and policy material, declassified government and United Nations documents, published and unpublished human rights reports from individuals and fellow non-governmental organizations (NGOs), press clippings and news releases, and maps. Another category of documents consists of HRW reports and briefing papers, as well as press releases and open letters to heads of state, governments and various government agencies.
Materials related to missions contain unpublished information on sources, cases, and the state of affairs in various countries. They include professional and personal mission notes taken by AW country researchers during investigative missions, testimonies by and interviews with victims of various human rights abuses, pre-mission and post-mission memos, addresses and contact lists.
Thematically, these documents deal with the various political and social transitions in Asia. The papers comprise such human rights advocacy initiatives as the attempt to alleviate the plight of political prisoners and refugees; the promotion of freedom of expression; the aftermath of the 1989 Tiananmen Square Massacre; the suppression of political violence in Indonesia and Sri Lanka; and the effect of Aids and prostitution on women.
Arrangement
This Record Group is arranged into 6 series:
Series 1: Series 1: Robin Munro
Series 2: Country Files, 1978-1997
Series 3: General Files, 1988-1997
Series 4: Jeannine Guthrie, Sri Lanka Files, 1985-1997
Series 5: Fraser Wood, China Files, 1989-1992
Series 6: Mickey Spiegel, China Files, 1985-1991.
Subjects
Human Rights Watch (Organization); United Nations--China.; Aung San Suu Kyi.; Afghanistan--History--1989-2001.; Bangkok (Thailand)--Social conditions.; Burma--Politics and government--1988-; Cambodia--Politics and government--1979-; China--Economic conditions--1976-2000.; China--Economic policy--1976-2000.; China--History--Tiananmen Square Incident, 1989.; China--Intellectual life.; China--Politics and government--1986-; China--Relations--Tibet.; Hong Kong (China)--History--Transfer of Sovereignty from Great Britain, 1997; Hong Kong (China)--Relations--China--Macau (Special Administrative Region); Human rights--India--Jammu and Kashmir.; Pakistan--Military policy.; Philippines--Military policy.; Philippines--Politics and government--1986-; Sarawak--Politics and government.; Singapore--Politics and government--1990-; Thailand--Foreign relations--1988-; United States--Foreign relations--China--Decision making.; Civil rights--Asia.; Dissenters--China.; Economic development--Moral and ethical aspects--Southeast Asia.; Family policy--China.; Freedom of expression--Asia.; Human rights--China--1989-; Human rights--Korea (South); Human rights--Philippines.; Human rights--Singapore.; Insurgency--Philippines.; Labor--China.; Malays (Asian people)--Malaysia--Sarawak.; Political atrocities--Timor-Leste.; Political persecution--China.; Political prisoners--Indonesia.; Political refugees--China.; Political refugees--Vietnam.; Political violence--Indonesia.; Political violence--Sri Lanka.; Prisoners--Civil rights--Japan.; Prisons--China.; Prisons--Japan.; Prostitution--Thailand.; Protest movements--China.; Refugees--Cambodia.
Access Restrictions
This collection is located off-site. Please consult the Rare Book and Manuscript Library for further information.
The records of Human Rights Watch are restricted and require the permission of the organization to view, copy, and/or publish. If you wish to request boxes from this collection, please send an email to rbml@columbia.edu detailing the collection, series, and box numbers in which you are interested. Once Human Rights Watch has reviewed the request, the scholar and the Rare Book and Manuscript Library will be contacted with specific instructions.
Acquisition
Human Rights Watch Deposit 2006
This material was originally deposited at the University of Colorado at Boulder by Human Rights Watch in the 1990s. The material was deposited with the Rare Book and Manuscript Library in 2006.
- Series 1: Robin Munro, China Files, 1979-1993
  This series contains files relating to Robin Munro's work as HRW/Asia Watch chief China researcher from 1989 to 1998. The alphabetically arranged files focus predominantly on the Tiananmen Square protests of 1989 and their aftermath. Files include materials on dissident intellectuals, drafts of articles and press reports.
  - The Anthems of Defeat: Crackdown in Hunan Province, 1989-1992 (Box 369, Folder 1)
  - Arrests Report, 1993 (Box 369, Folder 2)
  - Beijing Uprising and Massacre, 1989 June 3-4 (Box 369, Folder 3)
  - Bibliographies--Law, 1979-1987 (Box 369, Folder 4)
  - Book Proposal, 1991
    - The Black Hands of Beijing, 1991 (Box 369, Folder 5)
    - George Black, 1991 (Box 369, Folder 6)
  - Calculation of Prisoner Nos. by Category, undated (Box 369, Folder 7)
    (for "Cumulative Data" Report)
  - "The Case of Wang Jungtao", UCLA Pacific Basin Law Journal, 1991 (Box 369, Folder 7)
  - "China's Democracy Movement: A Midwinter Spring", Survey, 1984 (Box 369, Folder 8)
  - Chinese Ethnic Minorities, 1982-1987 (Box 369, Folder 9)
  - Communication, 1990-1991 (Box 369, Folder 10)
  - Contacts, 1990 (Box 369, Folder 11)
  - Criminal Investigations: Case Studies, 1981 undated, (2 folders) (Box 369, Folder 12-13)
  - Dissent--Press Clippings, 1988-1989 (Box 369, Folder 14)
  - Ethnic Minorities--Reports, 1987-1988, (2 folders) (Box 369, Folder 15-16)
  - Expenditure Accounting, undated (Box 369, Folder 17)
  - Faxes, 1991-1992 (Box 369, Folder 18)
  - Flyers and Handbills--Democracy Movement, 1989 (Box 369, Folder 19)
  - Human Rights Watch--Special Issue: The Crackdown in China, 1989 (Box 369, Folder 20)
  - Interoffice Mail, 1989 (Box 369, Folder 21)
  - Law Materials, undated (Box 369, Folder 22)
  - Lawyers--Legal Defense, 1987-1988 (Box 369, Folder 23)
    (Chinese)
  - Miscellaneous, 1989-1990 (Box 370, Folder 1)
  - Newsletters, 1989 (Box 370, Folder 2)
  - Outline for The Nation: "The Beijing Massacre", undated (Box 370, Folder 3)
  - "Political Persecution and the Legal System since June, 1990 (Box 370, Folder 4)
  - Press Coverage, 1990 (Box 370, Folder 5)
  - Press Reports, 1989-1990, (3 folders) (Box 370, Folder 6-8)
  - "The Real Story of the Slaughter in Beijing", The Nation, 1990 June 11 (Box 370, Folder 9)
  - Salary Memo, 1991 March 6 (Box 370, Folder 10)
    [restricted until 2067]
  - Sensitive Items, 1990 (Box 370, Folder 11)
  - Sources for Quotes, 1989-1990 (Box 370, Folder 12)
  - Talks, 1989-1990 (Box 370, Folder 13)
  - Torture Reports, 1989-1990 (Box 370, Folder 14)
  - Unidentified Materials, 1987-1991, (4 folders) (Box 370, Folder 15-18)
  - United States--Policy, 1989-1990 (Box 370, Folder 19)
  - "Who Died in Beijing, and Why", The Nation, 1990 June 11 (Box 370, Folder 20)
- Series 2: Country Files, 1978-1997
  Country files are arranged alphabetically and represent the following nations: Afghanistan, Australia, Bangladesh, Bhutan, Brunei, Burma, Cambodia, China, India, Indonesia, Japan, Laos, Maldives, Malaysia, Mongolia, Nepal, New Caledonia, North Korea, Pakistan, Philippines, Singapore, Sri Lanka, Taiwan, Tibet, and Vietnam. The files contain correspondence, mission notes and predominantly research files utilized in the compilation of Asia Watch publications and reports produced from 1987 to 1997.
  - Accountability, 1991-1991 (Box 371, Folder 1)
  - Asian Legal Resource Centre-"Use of Emergency Regulations in Peacetime in the Region," 1987 October 5-8 (Box 371, Folder 2)
  - Asian Migrant, 1994-1995 (Box 371, Folder 3)
  - Association of South East Asian Nations, 1989-1991 (Box 371, Folder 4)
  - Canadian Documentation Centre, 1989 (Box 371, Folder 5)
  - Foreign Broadcast Information Service (FBIS)--Daily Reports, 1988-1989, (3 folders) (Box 371, Folder 6-8)
  - Indochina, 1990-1991 (Box 371, Folder 9)
  - LAWASIA: Human Rights Bulletin, 1990 (Box 371, Folder 10)
  - "Looking East the Confucian Challenge to Western Liberalism", New Perspectives Quarterly, 1992 (Box 371, Folder 11)
  - Monitors Report, 1989 (Box 371, Folder 12)
  - "National Security Laws in Asia: An Overview", undated (Box 371, Folder 13)
  - Refugees
  - General, 1989-1992 (Box 371, Folder 14)
  - U.S. Committee for Refugees--Refugee Reports, 1989-1990 (Box 371, Folder 15)
  - U.S. Department of State--World Refugee Report, 1990 September (Box 371, Folder 16)
  - Women's Commission for Refugee Women and Children (Box 371, Folder 17)
  - Southeast Asia
  - General, 1989-1992, (2 folders) (Box 371, Folder 18-19)
  - Trade and Aid, 1992 (Box 371, Folder 20)
  - United States--Asia Policy, 1989-1995, (3 folders) (Box 371, Folder 21-23)
  - World Bank, 1990-1996, (3 folders) (Box 371, Folder 24-26)
  - World Wide Government Directory, 1989 (Box 371, Folder 27)
  - Afghanistan (Box 372)
    - Human Rights Watch (HRW)
    - Correspondence, 1991-1992 (Box 372, Folder 1)
    - Report:Afghanistan: The Forgotten War: Human Rights Abuses and Violations of the Laws of War Since the Soviet Withdrawal, 1991 February (Box 372, Folder 2)
    - Work, 1989-1993 (Box 372, Folder 3)
  - Afghan--Trip, 1990 (Box 372, Folder 4)
  - Afghan Information Centre Monthly Bulletin, 1987-1989 (Box 372, Folder 5)
  - Chronology, 1989-1992 (Box 372, Folder 6)
  - Contacts, 1989-1992 (Box 372, Folder 7)
  - Cooperation Centre for Afghanistan Newsletter (CCA), 1994-1995 (Box 372, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence, 1990-1995 (Box 372, Folder 9)
  - Foreign Relations, 1989-1992 (Box 372, Folder 10)
  - General
  - Background, 1989-1991 (Box 372, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence, 1988-1992, (3 folders) (Box 372, Folder 12-14)
  - Press Chronology, 1991-1993 (Box 372, Folder 15)
  - "Human Rights Abuses by Elements of the Afghan Resistance", 1989 (Box 372, Folder 16)
  - Human Rights Violations, 1992-1995 (Box 372, Folder 17)
  - International Human Rights Organizations, 1987-1991 (Box 372, Folder 18)
  - Killings, 1989-1992 (Box 372, Folder 19)
  - Land Issues, 1989-1991 (Box 372, Folder 20)
  - Landmines, 1989-1991 (Box 372, Folder 21)
  - Legal System/Texts, 1989-1990 (Box 372, Folder 22)
  - Les Nouvelles d'Afghanistan, 1989-1992 (Box 372, Folder 23)
  - Military and Government, 1989-1992 (Box 372, Folder 24)
  - Ministry of Justice Official Gazette, 1989-1990 (Box 373, Folder 1)
  - Missions Visits, 1989-1990 (Box 373, Folder 2)
  - Opposition Abuses, 1989-1992 (Box 373, Folder 3)
  - Political Opposition, 1989-1992 (Box 373, Folder 4)
  - Press, 1989-1992 (Box 373, Folder 5)
  - Prisons/Prisoners, 1989-1992 (Box 373, Folder 6)
  - Publications
  - General, 1989-1995 (Box 373, Folder 7)
  - Farsi, undated (Box 373, Folder 8)
  - Refugees, 1989-1992 (Box 373, Folder 9)
  - Reports, 1989 (Box 373, Folder 10)
  - Trade and Aid, 1989-1990 (Box 373, Folder 11)
  - United Nations, 1988-1995 (Box 373, Folder 12)
  - United States
  - Bush Report, 1991 (Box 373, Folder 13)
  - Congressional Advocacy, 1990-1991 (Box 373, Folder 14)
  - Policy, 1989-1992 1995 (Box 373, Folder 14)
  - Writers Union of Free Afghanistan (WUFA), 1989-1990 (Box 373, Folder 15)
  - Australasia
  - Opposition, 1989-1991 (Box 373, Folder 16)
  - Trade and Aid/Economic Policies, 1990 (Box 373, Folder 17)
  - Australia
  - Aborigines, 1990-1992 (Box 373, Folder 18)
  - Chron. File, 1992-1995, (2 folders) (Box 373, Folder 19-20)
  - Government, 1989-1993 (Box 373, Folder 21)
  - Publications, 1991-1993 (Box 373, Folder 22)
  - United Nations, 1994 (Box 373, Folder 23)
  - Bangladesh
  - Asia Watch--Work, 1989-1990 (Box 373, Folder 24)
  - Bangladesh and Burma, 1992 (Box 373, Folder 25)
  - Chittagong, 1992 (Box 373, Folder 26)
  - Correspondence, 1990 (Box 373, Folder 27)
  - Freedom of Expression--Taslima Nasrin Trial, 1993-1995 (Box 373, Folder 28)
  - General Background, 1988-1993, (4 folders) (Box 373, Folder 29-32)
  - Hindu Bauddha Christian United Council, 1992 (Box 373, Folder 33)
    (UK Branch)
  - Labor/Women, 1989-1990 (Box 373, Folder 34)
  - Liberty International, 1987-1991 (Box 373, Folder 35)
  - Map, undated (Box 373, Folder 36)
  - Publications, 1993-1994 (Box 374, Folder 1)
  - Rohingya--minority Muslim ethnic group
  - General, 1993-1995 (Box 374, Folder 2)
  - Interviews, 1992 (Box 374, Folder 3)
  - Repatriation, 1992-1994 (Box 374, Folder 4)
  - Trip--Notes, 1993 (Box 374, Folder 5)
  - Tribal/Ethnic, 1992-1994 (Box 374, Folder 6)
  - United Nations, 1993 (Box 374, Folder 7)
  - Bhutan
  - Background--General, 1992 (Box 374, Folder 8)
  - Communications w/Government, 1990-1993 (Box 374, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence--General, 1990-1993 (Box 374, Folder 10)
  - Freedom of Expression, 1991 (Box 374, Folder 11)
  - Legal System/Texts, 1987-1992 (Box 374, Folder 12)
  - Missions/Reports, 1993 (Box 374, Folder 13)
  - Prisons/Prisoners, 1992-1993 (Box 374, Folder 14)
  - Publications, 1990-1993 (Box 374, Folder 15)
  - Refugees, 1991-1993 (Box 374, Folder 16)
  - Brunei--Correspondence, 1990 (Box 374, Folder 17)
  - Burma
  - Asia Watch
  - Correspondence
  - Outgoing, 1993 (Box 374, Folder 18)
  - Sidney Jones and Mike Jendrzejczyk, 1992-1993, (2 folders) (Box 374, Folder 19-20)
  - "Recommendations for U.S. Policy", 1992 May (Box 374, Folder 21)
  - Reports, 1991-1993 (Box 374, Folder 22)
  - Statements on Burma, 1992 (Box 374, Folder 23)
  - Work, 1989-1991 (Box 374, Folder 24)
  - Academic Freedom, undated (Box 374, Folder 25)
  - Aid, 1991-1993 (Box 374, Folder 26)
  - AIDS
  - General, 1990-1993 (Box 374, Folder 27)
  - Problems, undated (Box 374, Folder 28)
  - All Burma Basic Education Students Union, 1994 (Box 374, Folder 29)
    (Thailand)
  - All Burma Students' Democratic Front Central Committee Headquarters (ABSDF), 1992-1994 (Box 374, Folder 30)
  - Amnesty International (AI) (Box 375)
  - General, 1991-1994 (Box 375, Folder 1)
  - Torture, 1990-1991 (Box 375, Folder 2)
  - Arakan News Bulletin, 1979-1992 (Box 375, Folder 3)
  - Arakan: Official Mouthpiece of Arakan Rohingya Islamic Front, 1990-1991 1993 (Box 375, Folder 4)
  - Arrests
  - General, 1993-1995 (Box 375, Folder 5)
  - Prisoners, 1989-1991 (Box 375, Folder 6)
  - Article 19 Bulletin: International Centre Against Censorship, 1992 1995-1996 (Box 375, Folder 7)
  - Articles, Reports, and Writings, 1989-1994, (2 folders) (Box 375, Folder 8-9)
  - ASKK Talks, 1991-1995 (Box 375, Folder 10)
  - Aung San Suu Kyi
  - Free Suu Kyi, Free Burma Campaign (FSFB), 1992, 1994, (2 folders) (Box 375, Folder 11-12)
  - Suu's Talk, 1994 August (Box 375, Folder 13)
  - Towards a True Refuge--Oxford Lecture, May 1993 (Box 375, Folder 14)
  - Background, 1992-1994 (Box 375, Folder 15)
  - Bangkok Post, 1990 May -November 1990 (Box 375, Folder 16)
  - Bangkok Post, 1990 December -1992 June (2 folders) (Box 376, Folder 1-2)
  - Boycotts--Pepsi & Amoco etc., 1993-1994 (Box 376, Folder 3)
  - B.U.R.M.A.: Burma Rights Movement for Action, 1991-1993 (Box 376, Folder 4)
  - Burma Action Group, 1992 (Box 376, Folder 5)
  - Burma Affairs Bulletin, 1991-1992 1994 (Box 376, Folder 6)
  - Burma Aktuell (Germany), 1991-1992 (Box 376, Folder 7)
  - Burma Alert (Canada), 1991-1996 (Box 376, Folder 8)
  - Burma Bureau (Germany), 1992 (Box 376, Folder 9)
  - Burma Chronology--Political Developments, 1994 (Box 376, Folder 10)
  - Burma Debate, 1994-1996 (Box 376, Folder 11)
  - Burma Focus, 1992-1994 (Box 376, Folder 12)
  - Burma Group Thailand, 1988-1990 (Box 376, Folder 13)
  - Burma Information Group, 1991-1993 (Box 376, Folder 14)
  - Burma Issues, 1993-1994 (Box 376, Folder 15)
  - Burma Meetings, 1991-1994, (2 folders) (Box 376, Folder 16-17)
  - Burma Monitor, 1991-1994 (Box 376, Folder 18)
  - Burma News Net, 1993-1994 (Box 376, Folder 19)
  - Burma Net News, 1994-1995, (7 folders) (Box 377, Folder 1-7)
  - Burma News Bulletin, 1992 (Box 377, Folder 8)
  - Burma Peace Foundation, 1993-1994 (Box 377, Folder 9)
  - Burma Press Summary, 1991-1993, (2 folders) (Box 378, Folder 1-2)
  - Burma Review, 1990-1995 (Box 378, Folder 3)
  - Burma-Thailand, 1990 (Box 378, Folder 4)
  - Burma: The German Connection, 1992 October (Box 378, Folder 5)
  - Burma Update, 1988 September -1992, (3 folders) (Box 378, Folder 6-8)
  - Burmese Relief Centre, 1991-1993 1995 (Box 378, Folder 9)
  - Burmese Students, 1988-1989 (Box 378, Folder 10)
  - Burmese Student Democratic Front, 1990-1991 (Box 378, Folder 11)
  - Caouette, Therese
  - Asia Watch--Documents, 1992-1994 (Box 378, Folder 12)
  - "Burmese Refugees in Thailand", 1991 December 13-15 (Box 378, Folder 13)
  - Correspondence and Outgoing Faxes, 1992-1995, (3 folders) (Box 378, Folder 14-16)
  - Free Expression Project, 1994 (Box 378, Folder 17)
  - Chronology and Background, 1987-1994 (Box 378, Folder 18)
  - Committee for Restoration of Democracy in Burma, 1991 1995 (Box 378, Folder 19)
  - Constitution of 1974 (Box 378, Folder 20)
  - Contacts, 1989-1991 (Box 378, Folder 21)
  - Correspondence and Incoming Faxes, 1989-1993, (3 folders) (Box 378, Folder 22-24)
  - Current Work, 1988-1990 (Box 378, Folder 25)
  - Dams Project, 1993-1995 (Box 379, Folder 1)
  - DAWN News Bulletin, 1989-1992 (Box 379, Folder 2)
  - Death Penalty, 1989 1991 (Box 379, Folder 3)
  - Democratic Alliance of Burma/National Coalition Government of the Union of Burma, 1991-1994 (Box 379, Folder 4)
  - The Democratic Forum, 1991 July (Box 379, Folder 5)
  - Demonstrations, 1989-1991 (Box 379, Folder 6)
  - Divestment Campaign, 1994-1995 (Box 379, Folder 7)
  - Dr. U Ne Oo--Refugees, 1993-1994 (Box 379, Folder 8)
  - Drugs
  - General, 1990-1991 1993-1995, (2 folders) (Box 379, Folder 9-10)
  - Conference on Narcotics in Burma, 1993 September 17 (Box 379, Folder 11)
  - Economy, 1992-1995 (Box 379, Folder 12)
  - Elections, 1990, (4 folders) (Box 379, Folder 13-16)
  - Environment--Research, 1990-1995 (Box 379, Folder 17)
  - Far East Economic Review--Asia Week, 1990-1993 (Box 379, Folder 18)
  - Foreign Broadcast Information Service (FBIS)--Daily Reports, 1989 1992 (Box 379, Folder 19)
  - Forced Labor
  - General, 1993-1994 (Box 379, Folder 20)
  - Ko Win Naing, 1993 (Box 379, Folder 21)
  - Foreign Investment, 1991-1995 (Box 379, Folder 22)
  - Foreign Relations, 1989-1991 (Box 379, Folder 23)
  - Franklin Research & Development Corporation, 1993-1995 (Box 379, Folder 24)
  - Friends of Burma at Harvard Newsletter, 1994-1995 (Box 379, Folder 25)
  - Gas Pipeline, 1991-1995 (Box 379, Folder 26)
  - General, 1990-1995, (5 folders) (Box 379, Folder 27-31)
  - General, 1993-1996, (3 folders) (Box 380, Folder 1-3)
  - General--Refugee Correspondence, 1995-1996 (Box 380, Folder 4)
    [restricted until 2072]
  - Human Rights Violations, 1989-1991 (Box 380, Folder 5)
  - "Human Rights Violations in Burma: Notes on Research Mission to Thai-Burma Border Areas", 1989 (Box 380, Folder 6)
  - International Centre for Human Rights and Democratic Development, 1994 (Box 380, Folder 7)
  - International Commission of Jurists (ICJ), 1992 (Box 380, Folder 8)
  - International Council of Voluntary Agencies (ICVA)--Mission to Burma Report, 1993 (Box 380, Folder 9)
  - International Human Rights Law Group, 1989-1992 (Box 380, Folder 10)
  - International Human Rights Organizations, 1992-1993 (Box 380, Folder 11)
  - International Law--Rape--Testimonies, 1992 (Box 380, Folder 12)
    [restricted until 2068]
  - International League for Human Rights, 1991 (Box 380, Folder 13)
  - International Negotiation Network, 1992 (Box 380, Folder 14)
    (Carter Center)
  - International Response
  - Arms to Burma, 1992-1994 (Box 380, Folder 15)
  - ASEAN on Burma, 1991-1995 (Box 380, Folder 16)
  - Australian Government on Burma, 1991-1995 (Box 380, Folder 17)
  - China, 1992-1995 (Box 380, Folder 18)
  - European Community, 1992-1995 (Box 380, Folder 19)
  - Japan, 1992-1995 (Box 380, Folder 20)
  - The Irrawaddy, 1993-1995 (Box 380, Folder 21)
  - Jesuit Refugee Service, 1991-1994, (3 folders) (Box 380, Folder 22-24)
  - Karen Human Rights Group
  - General, 1994-1995 (Box 380, Folder 25)
  - Reports, 1993-1994-1996, (2 folders) (Box 380, Folder 26-27)
  - Karen National Movement, 1947 1991 (Box 380, Folder 28)
  - Karen National Union, 1994-1995 (Box 380, Folder 29)
  - Karenni, 1988-1992 (Box 380, Folder 30)
  - Killings, 1989-1991 (Box 380, Folder 31)
  - Land Issues, 1991 (Box 380, Folder 32)
  - Laws, 1992 (Box 380, Folder 33)
  - Lawyers Committee for Human Rights, 1991-1992 (Box 380, Folder 34)
  - Legal System/Texts, 1989 (Box 380, Folder 35)
  - Logging, 1990-1994 (Box 380, Folder 36)
  - Mailing Lists, undated (Box 381, Folder 1)
  - Maps, Undated (Box 381, Folder 2)
  - Mekong Region, 1994-1995 (Box 381, Folder 3)
  - Military
  - Forced Migration by, 1990 (Box 381, Folder 4)
  - General, 1989 (Box 381, Folder 5)
  - Government, 1988-1991 (Box 381, Folder 6)
  - Miscellaneous
  - Articles, 1994 (Box 381, Folder 7)
  - State Law & Order Restoration Council (SLORC), 1991-1993 (Box 381, Folder 8)
  - Missions
  - Report and Notes, 1989 (Box 381, Folder 9)
  - Visits, 1988-1991 (Box 381, Folder 10)